Rajat Gupta

Fullstack Developer | Infosys

CONTACT ME



Muzaffarnagar, U.P. (INDIA) PIN: 251001



+91 8439192058



Gmail:

rajatgupta251001@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajat-gupta-0bb1bb171

SKILLS

JAVA

REACT

SPRING BOOT

DS/ ALGORITHMS

ANGULAR

EXPRESS JS

MYSQL

MONGODB

CI/CD - JENKINS

AGILE WORKFLOW

LANGUAGE

English

Hindi

PROFILE

Experienced Web Developer adept in full stack web development and working as polyglot developer. Knowledgeable in user interface, microservices designing and development, database integration, debugging processes. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Infosys, Bengaluru

(JUNE 2021 - PRESENT)

- Working with financial service provider client and collaborate with team of 8 members on various workflows, UI designing, development and maintenance.
- Migrate legacy UI to react with new features.
- Makes the UI accessible and ADA Compliant (means disable person can also access the application).
- API development and integration on spring boot.

MEAN Stack Developer, Infosys, Bengaluru

(NOV 2020 - JUNE 2021)

- Worked on e-commerce web application with team of 6 members.
- Develop, deploy and test seller components (like register, login, add products, orders etc) for the application on Angular 11 framework.
- Develop and design API's for the same seller part of the application and deploy to production environment using Express.js framework.
- Integrate API's with mongodb database.
- Implements JWT authentication in the microservices.

Full Stack Developer(Intern), WERP-INDIA, New Delhi

(JUN 2019 - AUG 2019)

- Works as frontend engineer for an African based non-profitable organization working for women empowerment with a team of 4 members.
- Design and develop UI of an web application on Angular Material.
- Conducted defect triage meetings with Business/Dev/Tester to optimize dev plans and strategies to deliver high quality deliverables within given timelines.

Full Stack Developer(Intern), KIET Group Of Institution, Ghaziabad

(SEP 2017 - FEB 2018)

- Works with a team of 4 members on the E-Learning (Web application) for the institution where faculty can upload documents, learning videos and interact with students.
- Develop UI of the application on react with API development on Spring Boot.
- Planning, constructing and deploy MYSQL database for the application.

EDUCATION

B.TECH (Information Technology) (AUG 2016 - SEP 2020)

From KIET Group of Intitutions, Ghaziabad with 80.8%

INTERMEDIATE (APR 2014 - MAY 2015)

From S.D. Public School, Muzaffarnagar with 84.8%

HIGH SCHOOL (APR 2012 - MAR 2013)

From S.D. Public School, Muzaffarnagar with 9.0 CGPA

ACHIEVEMENT & EXTRA-CURRICULAR

- Coordinate the college fest Epoque, Innotech etc.
- Develop 3D Hologram Fan for Digital Outdoor advertising.
- Received letter of recommendation from NSTEDB (National Science & Technology Entrepreneurship Development Board).
- Participated in various coding competitions and hackathons at various national and international level.